(Man A's ragged breathing)
(Man B)
S... stop! Stop it!
Aaaah!
(men shouting)
(gunfire)
(men and women screaming)
(Chang)
Enough!
Grab that and get out!
(Chang) Tch!
(Man A) Chang!
(Chang) Just as planned.
Hah... hah... hah...
(gunfire)
(Man A) Aaaah!
Guh! Ah! Ah!
(Officer A)
A high-traffic area detouring around the continental shelf...
(Officer B)
They all look suspicious.
(Navigator A)
It could well be a disguised ship.
(Officer A)
Communications?
(Communications Officer)
Ah... The XO has gone to ask the captain...
(XO)
Tell the chief engineer.
(Engineer) Yes, sir!
(Navigator A)
An Anaheim subsidiary, huh...
Hmm...
(Navigator B)
If we're right, a mobile suit will appear...
This ship will sink.
The navy today can't do a thing about it.
(XO)
Listen up!
From now on, this ship, like the Halmahera,
will search for fallen colony debris
that could serve as a base.
(Navigator B)
Again?
Just doing the Air Force's bidding, XO?
(XO)
Don't say that! It's the captain's decision.
(Navigator B)
The captain just doesn't want
the General Staff to come down on him.
(Navigator A)
Shh.
Whoosh.
(Fencer)
What do we do?
(Mechanic)
Keep fanning, keep fanning.
(Fencer)
Mm.
Heh heh heh.
(Crew D humming)
(Chartchai)
I know that much.
Ah... If we raise power output,
we'll be found out.
It's just as hot for us.
(curtain opens)
(Wedge) How is it?
(Chartchai)
Passive sonar: just one ping five minutes ago.
Communications...
It's not voice, so I can't tell.
(Crew C) Captain!
(Crew C)
The submarine is moving away.
(Wedge)
There you have it.
(Chartchai)
What about below?
Ah... just in case,
maintain alert for another 10 minutes.
(Chartchai)
Another 10... No, make it 20 minutes of alert.
(Wedge) Hmph!
This ship's got luck on its side!
(Crew) Yeah!
(Iram) Captain Wedge?
(Wedge) Yeah.
Hey...
Fortune
...
...Sheesh.
(Raymond) The ones deployed at Oenpelli
are, in fact—
They're a group unrelated to us.
(Hendrix) That's right.
We've been preparing
for the Adelaide Conference.
(Civet) But hey,
they're still part of the anti-Federation movement.
(Ridorick) Agreed.
(Raymond)
I can't ignore it either.
(Kelia) But if we help them,
what do we do afterwards?
(footsteps)
(Wedge) Quack Salver
used to say,
"When more people get involved,
things get complicated..."
(Raymond and others)
"It only leads to chaos."
(laughter)
(Hendrix) ...or something.
(Maximilian)
That's Mafty's catchphrase.
(Iram) More importantly,
covering this entire South Pacific—
Federation mobile suits are deployed.
We strike at the Kimberley unit at Oenpelli,
and stop the follow-up unit,
the Kirke at Davao, in its tracks.
Even stopping the main conference
becomes difficult.
...That's Hathaway's thinking.
(Kelia) But
if we get bogged down at Kimberley,
reinforcements might come
from Kenneth's unit, right?
(Wedge)
That risk is very real.
(Golf) Hah... hah... hah...
Hah... hah...
(Golf) According to Emeralda,
she was a real beauty.
(Gawman) I was too far away...
I couldn't tell.
Once more.
We'll keep at it until your body learns.
(Raymond)
If we engage at Oenpelli,
(Raymond) What about magazine resupply?
(Maximilian) No problem.
For the Messers, anyway.
(Iram) So,
to help you decide,
I'd like to explain the upcoming reinforcement points
and supplies.
Take a look.
I've had three points set up
on the wall.
(Civet)
Are we getting more pilots?
(Iram) I've put in a request.
(Wedge)
What about Mafty?
(Kelia) Fatigue seems to have caught up with him.
I've laid him down.
(Crewman A) The enemy spy—
that's about Hathaway's woman, right?
(Crewman B)
They spent the night in the same room.
You expect me to believe nothing happened?
(Crew A) Huh? No way.
(Crew B) Right?
(crew laughter)
(sound of door closing)
(Quess) You sensed something, didn't you?
Hathaway
(Hathaway) Yeah...
(Quess)
I wonder if he's still in Davao.
(Hathaway) This is
about how to handle Gigi inside me.
It's just a matter of deciding.
Hathaway Noah, huh...
(sound of Big Carrier's flight)
(Gigi) Kenneth is on the move too...
Let's change plans...
We'd better hurry.
Is this the only channel?
(Maid) It's different from space.
This is one of the better places.
Even though it's a fine night tonight.
Are you all alone?
(Cardeas) Most lives are
for the sake of one day's joy,
there are 365 days of patience.
(Gigi) What do you do?
(Cardeas) Someday, when you face
an unimaginable situation
so you won't make the wrong decision,
you have to obtain
some information beforehand.
Gigi.
If you have one truly good day,
you can endure a year of loneliness.
(Gigi) Mm...
(Cardeas)
That's what human life is like.
(female newscaster) The conference will be held
for three days starting on the 26th.
Since it's the first time in 13 years
that it's being held on Earth,
speculation that the government
may make some kind of announcement
is growing.
Along with this,
the newly appointed Commander Kenneth
is also drawing attention, it seems.
Now let's hear from reporter Lyle,
who covered the press conference.
(Lyle) With the arrival of the new commander,
Colonel Kenneth Sleg,
the Earth Federation Forces stationed in Davao
from Kimberley Unit
to Kirke Unit
announced that it would change its designation.
(Gigi) I know that...
(Gigi)
Everyone's keeping it a secret...
(Analyst) The new commander's arrival
(sound of Big Carrier's flight)
This can be seen as a move aimed at
the upcoming Adelaide Conference.
(sound of Big Carrier's flight)
Concern over holding it on Earth,
where anti-Federation organizations are active—
To also suppress the voices of Federation lawmakers,
the stability of the Federation Forces in Oceania
is required.
(Intelligence Officer B)
Water depth exceeds 6,000 meters.
Early retrieval appears difficult.
(Minecche) Next!
(Kenneth) Mafty's base?
(Intelligence Officer B) Today at 0808 hours.
The 7th Fighter-Attack Squadron found it and landed.
What Mafty calls the 'tree' of Rodoiseya—
It appears to be one of their bases...
(Kenneth) And?
(Intelligence Officer B) The interior was completely empty.
We're expanding the search area to a 300-kilometer radius...
Threaten the Navy if you must—make them search for the other bases.
By order of the Joint Chiefs of Staff!
(Intelligence Officer B) Yes, sir.
(Kenneth) Next!
(Intelligence Officer C) Here are the images of the craft.
(controls beep)
(Kenneth) A Gundam imitation...
(Intelligence Officer C)
We processed it, but this is the best we can do.
A unit they protected even at the cost of abandoning one of their bases.
So we must consider it a combat capability on par with the Penelope.
(Intelligence Officer C) Yes, sir.
I want to review Adelaide's defense system.
Where is Lieutenant Colonel Mainzer?
(Minecche) I've called for him.
(Intelligence Officer C) Colonel Kenneth.
(Kenneth)
What about the records from Lane's submerged unit?
(Intelligence Officer C) Recovery will take about two weeks...
(Kenneth) Three days.
Have it ready before the conference.
Your career is on the line.
(Intelligence Officer C) Yes, sir.
(Minecche)
As expected, it's Anaheim?
(Kenneth) Most likely.
(Minecche)
Regarding Lieutenant Lane's use of the experimental model.
It was approved, then.
Yeah, by the conference, he—
He must become a combat asset.
(Lagoid) Please wait just a little longer!
(Lagoid)
Please wait just a little longer!
He has arrived!
Director Hundley Yeoksan
(Maintenance Crew C) Where are you going?
(Maintenance Crew D) At this hour, nothing's open.
(Mechanic)
Flight units five and eight—
We're rebuilding them with brand-new cores!
Hurry up!
Don't worry.
It'll have to be transported, but we'll make it in time for the conference.
Until then, please make do with the Aryuzeus.
(Lane) Sorry for the trouble.
(Lane, voiceover) That was because of Kenneth's orders.
It was the guilt of having used a hostage.
(Lane) Agh!
(Kenneth) Listen up!
There's no room for honor.
The ones who win
become justice.
Burn that into your heart!!
Lane Aim!!
I won't be beaten
by a Gundam wannabe again...
Or by those adults...
(Yeoksan)
Lieutenant Lane Aim, wasn't it?
You want me to help
round up illegal residents?
(Yeoksan) Over a single prisoner,
the man tasked with defending the Cabinet Council—
I have no intention
of dragging you down.
Even I, when it comes to the Federation government's
recent attitude toward Earth management—
do not necessarily agree with it.
(Kenneth)
The head of Man Hunter...
How dare you!
(Kelia) Did you take your medicine?
(Hathaway) It makes my head all foggy,
so I don't want to take it.
(Kelia) Are you really going out?
What Kimberley is doing
in Oenpelli—
I have to confirm it.
It might be useful for our future activities.
(Kelia)
Your head is full of nothing but ideology...
That's exactly why they've
put you up as Mafty.
You do realize that, right?
It's something
someone has to do.
For a powerless organization,
there's no other way.
So the organization is to blame?
(Hathaway)
Right now, this is all I can manage.
You of all people should understand.
You should just take it...
(eating sounds)
(Hathaway) Mm...
(Hathaway) Mm... mmm...
(eating sounds)
(Mihessia)
It was originally "Oenpelli",
but after some official messed up,
the "p" became a "b".
(Emeralda) Huh.
(Golf)
What the hell? It's packed.
(Lulu)
...So what's the deal?
(Emeralda) I don't know.
(Betchy)
Word is, it ended ages ago.
(Hala) Really?
(hair clipper buzzing)
(Mihessia)
That was a move to figure out
who she really was.
(Golf)
You're the only one who believes that.
(Emeralda) Don't "you" me!
(Hala)
So you're saying he had no choice but
to say that, given his position?
(Golf)
Pretty much.
(Mihessia) Hm? Oh!
Sorry!
(Hathaway) It's below.
(Mihessia) Yes!
What about Oenpelli?
(Hathaway)
What do you think, Mihessia?
As General Quack is also pleased,
and to build momentum for the anti-Federation movement,
I believe they are a group we must value.
You're saying we shouldn't ignore them?
(Mihessia)
No, it's a difficult call.
And we've also received word
about the conference venue change...
(Mechanic C) Is the I-field's shape collapsing?
(Member E) Hmm...
(Maximilian)
Try restarting it again.
If not, we'll swap it with the Byno.
(Mechanic B) Got it.
(Hathaway) What's wrong?
(Member E) The main engine's I-field isn't working properly,
so it forces a shutdown.
(Maximilian) Hm...
(Mihessia) What do you mean?
(Hathaway) That's called a Minovsky-
Ionesco type thermonuclear reactor.
By using the I-field for electromagnetic induction
inside the reactor,
it stabilizes the plasma.
(Member E)
At the same time, the I-field
confines high-speed neutrons inside the reactor.
(Mihessia) So that's why it shuts down...
Then without Minovsky particles,
mobile suits can't operate?
Well, that's about right.
I learned something!
(Member E) The central density of the potential well
is dropping, right?
the Coulomb barrier's
tunnel-effect area
hasn't been reached.
It hasn't been reached.
(Hathaway)
What about Gawman?
(Maximilian)
There's an M-Messer at Sealac,
so he went to take a look.
(Betchy) Whoa! Hahaha!
(Gawman) Hahaha! Whoa!
(Hathaway) The M-type throttle quirk
hasn't been fixed, right?
(Maximilian)
Because Eme won't give it up!
(Hathaway) Hmm...
(Maximilian)
Hathaway, about Oenpelli...
(Hathaway)
Are you also in the stay camp?
No, the missile cargo recovery rate
is low.
Considering the operation, we can't use funnel missiles.
I see...
You've heard from Kelia, haven't you?
(Hathaway) Yeah...
I'll keep that in mind.
(Hathaway) What about Oenpelli?
(Josef) No change.
(Chartchai)
Weren't they wiped out?
It's not that simple.
It could just be that their radio was hit.
(Josef)
It's still serious either way.
(Chartchai)
And then there's this.
The radio traffic from Davao
to Guangzhou and Hong Kong
The problem is, it's been increasing.
An order to gather ground troops
and police in Guangzhou, right?
(Hathaway)
Guangzhou...
The Federation cabinet ministers like it there.
(Chartchai)
Iram says it's staged too.
It could be made to look like
the conference is being moved from Adelaide, but...
It's too obvious.
(Crew D)
The captain's saying
the same kind of thing, y'know.
Either way, we're sortieing.
Keep intercepting their communications.
(Chartchai)
So all of this is a diversion?
(Maximilian)
Xi
will be brought up first.
(Hathaway)
So it can launch?
(Maximilian)
Yeah. Head up to the aft deck.
(Hathaway)
What about the barrier capability check?
Leave it to Julia.
(Hathaway) Mm...
(Kelia) Oh...
(Kelia) Hathaway!
(Hathaway) What?
(Kelia) What...? It's nothing.
(Hathaway)
You, of all people, should understand.
(Kelia) What happened?
With that girl... Gigi, or whatever her name is.
(Hathaway)
I came into contact with a dangerous girl.
And I couldn't eliminate her.
I had no choice but to board the Xi.
That's what's eating at me.
(Kelia) I heard that.
(Hathaway) It's the truth.
(Kelia) Yes, I know
you wouldn't lie.
Besides...
probabilistically speaking...
You can get by without lying, can't you?
(Hathaway) Hah...
Hathaway!
Have you started hating me?
This isn't something
that can be reduced to like or hate.
But...
when you come at me like that...
(Kelia) Hathaway...!
Sorry. Let me work for now.
(Kelia)
You made this work for yourself...!
Then you do it.
(Crew) Huh? What do we do?
(Wedge) Hm... Tch...
We're supposed to reach Oenpelli
by sunset, aren't we?
(Raymond) What's the status
on the assault team's boarding?
(Mihessia) From Sealuck!
The Galcezon's launch
looks OK.
(Wedge)
Where's Hathaway's Gundam?
(Iram) Hathaway!
Launch the Kirke unit!
(Hathaway) Go ahead!
Julia's on edge!
(Iram) Captain!
(Wedge) Do it!
If we keep dawdling,
reinforcements from Davao will show up!
(Civet)
How's the M-type treating you?
It's still got a lot of quirks, but
Just right for an old-timer.
Launch, Civet!
Hey!
Second Galcezon, launching!
(Civet and the others whoop)
(Wedge)
Those damn brats!
(Raymond) Iram!
The first one's good to go!
(Iram) Roger.
Captain, Iram and I
talked it over, but...
(Raymond)
First Galcezon, launching!
(Hathaway)
Julia! Hurry!
(Julia) I know.
It's almost done!
(Hathaway) Ah...
I told you to at least put on a T-shirt.
(Julia) More importantly—
What's with this reckless plan?
I can't agree with the assault team selection either!
(Hathaway) You think?
Mihessia's read on people
is pretty sharp.
(Julia)
But still, Kimberley...
They're trained soldiers...
Look.
(Hathaway)
Yeah... I know, but
Put something on so those lovely breasts don't get hurt!
(Julia) Only men get
to go topless.
We didn't used to wear these
either, back in the day.
(Julia) Hmph!
(Crew) Pfft!
Hathaway!
You're
going to fall!
(Hathaway) Aaaah!
♪~
♪ I'll touch that fire for you
♪ I do that 3, 4, times again
I testify for you
♪ I told that lie
I'd kill that bitch, I do what
♪ All of them around you
scared to do I'm not
♪ Long as you juggin out here
for me I got it
♪ Mobbin scheming looting
hide your bodies
♪ Long as you dreaming about me
ain't no problem
♪ I don't got nobody
just with you right now
♪ To tell the truth
I look better under you
♪ I can't lose when I'm with you
♪ How can I snooze
and miss the moment
♪ You just too important
♪ Nobody do body like you do
♪ I can't lose when I'm with you
♪ I can't just snooze
and miss the moment
♪ You just too important
♪ Nobody do body like you do you do
♪ Main one, riding
♪ How you fronting on me
and I'm the main one trying?
♪ How you blame it on me
and you the main one lying?
♪ How you threatening to leave
and I'm the main one crying?
♪ Just trying to be your everything
♪ I can lose, oh
♪ I think I know, ooh-woah
(incoming transmission beep)
(Maximilian) The unit's barrier capability
seems fine.
Releasing the line.
(Hathaway) Right.
Hah...
Hah... hah...
This is a mission we might not come back from.
(Iram) We're almost there, aren't we?
You call that talking it over with me?
We've come this far
together, haven't we?
So you really are in love.
(Kelia) Stop it.
(Iram) Fine.
I'll see it through to the end
even if I'm alone.
(Kelia) Take care.
(Iram) Huh?
(Kelia) That girl, Gigi...
(Kelia) She might erase Quess.
I have a feeling.
Hah...
(Hathaway, voiceover) At this rate,
I'll become a thoroughly selfish man.
(Hathaway, voiceover) But I will definitely
see Gigi Andalusia again.
(Hathaway, voiceover) Until then,
I can't afford to be careless.
(Iram) Even if Kimberley anticipates
our support,
an incursion from this bearing
is a route they won't expect.
The enemy will likely figure we'll use
the mountains east of Oenpelli as cover,
and approach.
We'll cross 200 kilometers of sea
in just under ten minutes, then enter the wetlands.
Oenpelli lies tens of kilometers
inland from the coast, but
it's practically at sea level.
It's also a dangerous approach bearing
with long sightlines.
(Hathaway) Recon.
(Raymond and others) Roger.
(Hathaway) It's Oenpelli.
(alarm)
(Hathaway) Kimberley...!
(Raymond)
Golf's feed is in.
Betchy
(Betchy) Whoa... This is...
(Raymond)
The private army's been wiped out, it seems.
(Hathaway) Is this a corpse?
(Emeralda)
What else could it be?
(Raymond) Damn Kimberley.
He's rattled
because Kenneth showed up.
(Gawman) Hey!
This one's moving toward Jabiru...
(Hathaway) Yeah...
So that's the self-proclaimed Mafty army.
(Civet)
They still have troops left?
(Raymond) The number Kimberley beat to death—
In the thousands, I'd say.
(Hala) Are you sure?
(Raymond) Even at the camps outside the city,
there are corpses strewn about
by the hundreds.
(Hathaway) Understood, but
this will be a head-on fight!
(Gawman) That's what we came here for!
(Golf) It's all good!
(Civet) We'll show them.
(Hathaway) It'll be rough.
This is no sneak attack, you know.
(Fencer) A head-on fight's just fine!
(Golf and the others shout)
(Gawman)
Here we go, Hathaway!
(impact sound)
(Pilot) Whoa!
(Hathaway) Are they running?
(explosion)
(alarm)
(incoming transmission beep)
(Gawman)
We're going after the Oenpelli forces!
(Hathaway) Go after them!
Hala, put out the fire!
(Hala) Roger.
(Hathaway) Move and I'll burn you with a beam.
After what you've done,
you have no right to complain!
(Hathaway) This was
one-sided, wasn't it?
Everything's gone mad.
(incoming transmission beep)
(Raymond) Hathaway,
we've located the enemy hideout.
(Betchy) Over there!
(Hathaway) Yeah!
(Hathaway) What's inside?
(Rod) Clear.
(Rod) The Federation administrative staff
and mechanics who were inside—
They've surrendered.
(Hathaway) What about the food supplies?
(Rod) They're all gone.
It reeks, doesn't it?
There were prisoners here, see?
Looks like they were beaten pretty badly.
(Hathaway) Torture...
(Emeralda)
Is Hathaway here?
(Hathaway)
I'm here!
(Mechanic A)
Come this way.
(Hathaway)
Yeah...
(Rod)
Apparently someone's still alive in the back.
(Hathaway)
I see...
(Hala)
I'll grab some water.
(Emeralda)
Please.
(Hathaway)
A woman?
(Emeralda)
Yeah. She's in terrible shape.
Even if she survives, she might kill herself.
(Hathaway)
What's the situation here?
(Emeralda)
Hala, explain it to him.
(Hala)
This floor appears to have been used
to hold prisoners.
She's the only survivor.
There are over thirty bodies, just from what we've confirmed.
(Hathaway)
What about the Federation troops?
(Hala)
They're on the floor above.
It looks like they came in from the rooftop
in Gustav Karls.
(Hathaway)
Let's bring them here as prisoners.
(Hala)
What?!
(Hathaway)
We have to do at least that, don't we?
It's unpleasant, but...
(Gigi)
I want to go to Hong Kong early tomorrow.
Is there a flight?
(Kenneth)
What? You're leaving already?
(Gigi)
I have work too, you know.
I want to settle things for the Count.
That way, I might be able to...
come back here again.
I might be able to come back...
Listen... on my end...
(Gigi) But yesterday and today...
(Gigi)
But yesterday and today...
Quite a few transport planes have been leaving, haven't they?
Back and forth.
Are you spying?
(Gigi)
For whom?
(Kenneth)
For Hathaway, right?
(Gigi)
If I'm here,
I can see the transport planes leaving the base.
You know that, Colonel.
(Kenneth)
All right.
I thought the reason the Adelaide support operation
has gone well so far...
was because you were here...
(Gigi)
I'm glad you think so.
(Kenneth) What time does C38 depart tomorrow?
(Gigi)
But even if I come see you now...
you won't see me?
Not tonight. Tomorrow I can come get you.
(Gigi)
Boring.
How boring...
But Gigi
That's life.
(Hathaway)
How did it come to this?
Colonel Kimberley Heyman
(Kimberley) No comment.
Mafty Navue Erin
(Raymond) We don't have truth serum either.
Shall we torture them?
(Hathaway) If I let that happen,
I'd have the Oenpelli troops do it.
(the three) Ugh...
(Gawman) They're waiting below.
(Major) You're handing us over to them?!
(Hathaway)
The people you detained here...
If they knew how you dealt with them,
they'd certainly retaliate.
(Major) Please, not that.
(Kimberley) They're the ones...
who cut our pilots to pieces.
This was meant as a warning to them!
(Hala)
Lame. This is a kids' fight.
(Kimberley, Major) Ugh...
(Gawman) What do we do with them?
(Hathaway) They'll slow us down,
but we can use them for prisoner exchange.
(Gawman) Still hung up on that?
(Hathaway)
Until that kind of thing happened...
I couldn't even imagine it.
That's what frustrates me.
(Gawman) Aren't you too naive?
(Hathaway) Maybe so...
(Gawman)
Fabio! Fabio Rivera!
He's Mafty.
(Oenpelli soldier) Mafty...
(Fabio) Which one?
(Hathaway) So it's you?
The man who was posing as Mafty.
(Fabio) Heh... Geez.
If this isn't a joke,
I was using some rookie's name
without knowing it.
Seems I've dragged my own name down.
What?!
(Oenpelli soldiers' laughter)
(Hathaway) That's because you lack imagination.
(Fabio) What did you say?
(Hathaway) But the same goes for me.
If there was someone impersonating Mafty,
I thought it would be someone intelligent.
If possible,
I'd like to meet that leader.
Did he die?
(Fabio) What makes you say that?
(Hathaway) A person like that...
would fight a mobile suit with just a pistol.
It wouldn't be surprising if he died on this battlefield.
(Fabio) I, Fabio Rivera—
gave the order to set up
a resistance line in this land!
It was only because I myself
held the ideals of the anti-Federation movement!
That's why I didn't run.
We didn't even have a way
to contact Quack Salver,
we didn't know how.
(Federico) Fabio!
As much as that kid says,
we haven't failed.
Once the video reaches space,
the wind will blow our way again.
(Hathaway) What do you mean?!
(Fabio) With footage of the massacre
Kimberley carried out,
our comrades are heading into space.
(Gawman) They'll never make it.
(Chang) Not every one of us
is an illegal squatter.
(Hathaway)
What's on it? Is there a copy?
(Federico) We didn't have time for that.
(Meihou) Look,
our retreat was cut off,
we were trampled and crushed
by mobile suits!
(Hathaway) With mobile suits?
(Meihou) Yeah. Kimberley toyed with us!
(Hathaway) Even as a warning,
that's hard to believe…
(Federico) It's no use, Meihou.
They only see our suffering
from over their robots' heads.
They're no different from Kimberley.
(Gawman) You bastard!
(Hathaway) We're pulling out of here.
Take the three to Galcezon's B cabin.
(Raymond)
Got it. What about the rest?
(Gawman) If we leave them behind,
who knows what Fabio's people will do.
(Hathaway) For now, we'll have to take them
and release them somewhere.
(Member) Hey, get up.
(Major) Ugh…
(Hathaway) We're pulling out. Let's take him in.
(Emeralda) He's dead.
Let his comrades bury him.
(Hathaway) That would be better…
(Kenneth)
We let Mafty slip away.
If we'd caught up to them at Oenpelli
yesterday,
we could have wiped them out.
On top of that, you have to escort cabinet ministers too.
That's a burden.
(Kenneth) Yeah, but no matter how rotten,
they're still called cabinet ministers.
They still order us to spread dummy intel,
so it gets in the way of real work.
(Kenneth) Gigi.
(Gigi) What? About the escort duty?
Yeah.
Why did you think that?
I never said anything about
escorting cabinet ministers just now.
(Gigi) I don't know.
I just thought so.
The way my heart feels lonely…
It's the same as not being able to explain.
Hey, tell me Hathaway Noa's
address.
Are you going to see him?
(Gigi) Hmph...
Manado?
It's way south.
From here on, it's islands, islands, islands.
It's all islands all the way to Australia.
It's like a space colony.
(Gigi) That's right.
The sealed environment of a colony
may have narrowed human reason, but
I felt it's the same even on Earth.
To me, gravity seems really oppressive.
So, you know, going out into space
was inevitable.
I think it's a good thing
that humans thought of that.
Yeah. With a little more training...
all humans might be able
to become Newtypes.
(Gigi) You're a religious man, Colonel.
Hardly.
I'm talking about a quality
humans are born with.
But why would a colonel like you
get so violent?
Violent?
(Gigi)
Or, to put it another way, explosiveness?
(Kenneth) You're kind.
It's frustration, right?
Having a body, having emotions...
a dull human who can't reach enlightenment...
Because I'm an Oldtype,
that's why I get irritated.
Mafty too?
Probably...
Yeah.
(Bureaucrat A) The military has it tough, too.
Seems they're putting on a show,
flying plane after plane
through this sky.
(Bureaucrat C) To Hong Kong?
(Bureaucrat D) Picking up the minister's family
and escorting them straight to Adelaide.
(Bureaucrat C) That's rough...
(Bureaucrat D) Heh. What about you?
(Bureaucrat C) I'm in the second half of the conference,
so I'll head to Adelaide in a week.
(Kimberley soldier) Nn...
We've been set free, huh...
(Hathaway)
See you at the wall! Gawman.
Take the Sea Rack!
Mafty too!
(Gigi) More than Davao?
(Wave) Especially the places Lady Gigi
is about to visit...
Using a limousine is
a privileged act.
(civilian)
Please stop it!
You'd better tip the driver
in advance.
(Man Hunter)
Don't move!
(Gigi) Even if a soldier like you asks?
Yes, the Federation government's crackdown
is making ordinary people violent
in some places.
Retaliation using Man Hunters and the like
will come to the privileged class.
(Minister) When I got off the ship,
I thought I'd stepped into the water.
(Friend) This slimy stuff
is Earth.
(Wave) Sorry to keep you waiting!
Ms. Mace Flower,
this way, please.
(Driver) Even so,
compared to the old century's prosperity,
it's only a tenth.
But the Federation government's recent
push to return to Earth
is remarkable.
(Driver)
The Universal Century is
already a century old.
They say Earth's pollution has eased, so
even in the city and in high-class residential areas like this,
government officials... ah...
(Gigi) It's fine. I'm not
from that class.
I'm just someone with the pathetic job
of being a mistress.
(Driver) Oh... Hahaha...
Hearing you say that
makes me feel better.
(Guard) Only residents are allowed in.
(Gigi) Gigi Andalusia...
Surely you've heard of me?
(Guard) Oh!
You arrived later than expected.
We were worried.
I came down on the Haunzen Flight.
(gate opens)
(Caretaker) Your room is on the top floor.
The view
is simply wonderful.
(Gigi) I should hope so.
If I'm disappointed,
there'd be no point in coming
to a place like this.
(Caretaker) Quite right...
(Caretaker) I've had the minimum preparations done,
such as making the bed.
If you need new things,
I'll call a contractor right away.
(Gigi) The elevator?
(Caretaker) Yes!
This way!
(Caretaker) Here we go.
You're welcome to purchase the furniture as is.
We also have catalogs available.
(Gigi) I see.
♪～
♪ I had a sudden feeling.
♪ Before the magic fades
♪ I want to blend together and know
♪ Unmixed expectations
♪ With a feigned attitude
♪ With my real feelings about to fade
♪ I can't keep up the act anymore
♪ In front of you, I distort
♪ Steal me to go
♪ The boiling STROKE
♪ Even in a world that bypassed the right answer
♪ Divert me so
♪ The PAST I entrusted
♪ Even a wish clouded by afterimages is fine
♪ Cuz I define you
lying with your breath
♪ A blue about to overflow and burst
♪ I want to touch you more selfishly and it hurts
♪ If we sink while embracing
♪ Steal me to go
♪ The boiling STROKE
♪ Even in a world that bypassed the right answer
♪ Divert me so
♪ The PAST I entrusted
♪ Even a wish clouded by afterimages is fine
♪ Cuz I define you
lying with your breath
♪ A blue about to overflow and burst
(Gigi) Hah!
Hathaway, huh...
(sound of entering the bath)
(Gigi) Hathaway Noa
Hathaway Noa
Hathaway, huh...
(Gigi, voiceover)
I can't face Grandfather...
(Hathaway) Did you send Kelia
to Darwin?
(Iram) Yeah.
The captain complained, but
there are also preparations over there
to receive them,
so I sent her with Julia.
Julia?
Those two, who don't get along?
(Amuro) After you've smelled the stench of death,
you worry about Kelia?
(Hathaway)
I'm supposed to have a great cause—
to give the world
the impact of social reform.
Gigi was meant for that...
(Quess)
No one's going to believe that!
(Hathaway) Yeah...
Somehow, I have to break away
from this body and these emotional desires,
or I won't be saved...
(Iram)
That'll be the last of that.
(Hathaway) Huh?
(Iram) Kelia
procured it for you, didn't she?
I see.
You regret it now, don't you?
(Hathaway)
Stop it, I give, I give!
(both laugh)
(Hathaway) Heh.
(Iram)
Since then, Davao and Hong Kong
radio exchanges with Guangzhou
have become more and more contrived.
But there are also a lot of southbound transport planes.
We still can't rule out
that both are diversions.
(Hathaway)
But there isn't that much leeway
even for the Kirke unit.
(Iram) I suppose so, but—
Since Kenneth Sleg arrived,
Davao's movements have been
remarkably active.
He's certainly a capable operator.
Hm... is that so?
At Bynoe, at least,
there'll be some resupply, right?
(Iram) Yeah, that's the plan.
They'll take care of the
Heso Point and Gora matter.
(Iram) Kelia, she...
(Hathaway) Oof!
(Hathaway) Nngh!
(Kenneth) Hm... heh heh.
(Mace) Heheheh...
(Clerk) I'll put you through.
(phone hold music)
(hold music)
(Gigi) Is Hathaway Noa in?
(a man resembling Amada) No, he's out.
He's out on field training.
He isn't here.
Are you Professor Amada Mansan?
(a man resembling Amada) Who may I ask is calling?
(Gigi)
My name is Gigi Andalucia.
(a man resembling Amada) I've heard the name.
Where are you calling from?
(Gigi) Hong Kong.
Actually, I'd love to visit you there, but...
Could you pass a message to Hathaway?
(a man resembling Amada) Certainly.
Tell him our next date—
let's make it Adelaide.
(a man resembling Amada)
A date in Adelaide?
That's rather out of the blue.
(Gigi) We decided that yesterday.
We couldn't decide on our next meeting in Davao...
(a man resembling Amada) His work takes him
to places with no phones, so...
Unless I hear from him,
there's nothing I can do.
(Gigi) I don't know yet
what I'll do either.
I might go to Uncle Kenneth's place...
(a man resembling Amada) Uncle Kenneth?
Ah... You're a busy one, aren't you?
That's right.
I have a lot of fans, don't I?
But I'm glad
this call got through...
Can I call you again?
(a man resembling Amada) I don't mind that, but...
(Gigi, voiceover) It's all right, isn't it...
(Yeoksan) Thank you for your cooperation
in yesterday's operation.
No, not at all.
While we'll be away for a while,
we wanted things kept quiet.
(Hugest) Indeed.
(Kenneth) Mm.
(Lagoid)
Yes, sir! Here!
(Yeoksan) For someone stuck
on Earth, he's quite capable.
I thought you'd also
be pulled into the military.
You're Bright Noa's son, aren't you?
He seems to have returned to Menado.
Did you track him?
Even if the passengers of that craft
are cabinet ministers' families,
we still track them.
Man Hunter is a tough job.
I see...
How dull...
(Yeoksan)
Heh... Right, that girl Gigi.
You were right to stay away from her.
If you get involved with Cardeas,
you'll have no future as an officer.
(Kenneth) I'll take that to heart.
(Yeoksan) I see.
(Jose) This woman Mace is
on the Haunzen as
a CA.
Her identity is guaranteed, I hear.
(Silva) What's the source?
(Jose) A reliable source:
Lieutenant Ray Lagoid.
(laughter)
(Okamura) What's that?
(Sojin) Rejected.
She's an illegal resident
living in Hong Kong,
sent to get information
from Kenneth.
A spy dispatched by Mafty.
(Eikka) That's just great.
(laughter)
(Sojin) It's funny, right?
(announcer) This time,
the Kirke unit and the police organization
jointly commanded
a sweep operation against subversive elements.
It appears there were over 500 arrests
and over 100 deaths.
The military and Man Hunter...
What's going on, Kenneth?
(female newscaster)
Pollution remediation in the Southern Hemisphere...
(weather forecaster)
The westerlies, which have been meandering greatly...
(both laugh)
(narrator)
Space colonies...
(Gigi) Even if I stay here,
I can't hear the truth.
(female newscaster)
That's all for today.
Have a good day tomorrow.
Good night.
(alarm)
(Gigi) Mm! Mm!
I'm sorry.
I still want to live a little longer.
This is my fate.
(Gigi, voiceover) I feel sorry for the Count, too.
Adieu, my patron.
I...
may be going to my death.
(Hathaway) From the professor?
(Wedge) Yeah.
If the decryption is correct.
Apparently, no change—
it's still Adelaide.
(Hathaway) Gigi?
I see. So it came from her...
(Wedge) Is she all right?
(Hathaway) That girl, in the sense that
her mood changes constantly...
she seems special.
(Wedge) Is that so?
You know her? Gigi?
Girls like Gigi aren't rare.
(Hathaway)
There's one interesting possibility.
(Wedge) Oh?
Fabio Rivera and his people
may be moving into
Bynoe Harbour.
How do they see
Kirke's movements?
(Hathaway) They'll see it as a diversion
to keep us pinned on that continent.
In that sense,
Fabio and his people are too clever.
(Iram) Since right after Hathaway
landed in Davao,
communications between Davao and Hong Kong
have been on the rise.
There are reports the Federation cabinet meeting
has been moved to Kwangchow.
There's reason to believe that.
Hundley Yeoksan of the Criminal Police Organization
is sharp, too.
It was him and Kenneth
who set the Man Hunter in motion, right?
So that means today or tomorrow
all cabinet ministers
will move to Adelaide.
Right.
Around Hong Kong,
how many were there?
(Wedge)
About twelve, I'd say.
There are flights from South America, too,
so transport capacity has been built up.
But the enemy's insistence
on Adelaide for the cabinet meeting—
What's their scheme?
Using the Kirke unit
and the Criminal Police Organization,
they intend to crush us completely.
The Federation government believes
it's in command,
so
that's why it's Adelaide.
That's your gut feeling from meeting
the cabinet ministers?
(Hathaway) Yeah.
(Wedge) I don't get it...
Somehow your thinking
feels... insular.
(Iram)
That's why it's 'overthrow the Federation government,' right!
Hathaway!
(Hathaway) Yeah.
Is Gigi really that...
(Wedge) I don't know her.
That's how Mihessia and the others rate her.
Mihessia's the type who feels too much.
She's not much use as a reference.
(Wedge) Is that so?
(Hathaway) It's fine.
(Iram) The crew assignments for each Base Jabber
are as listed.
After resupplying at Bynoe,
we split into four teams
and head for Navel Point.
(Emeralda) Aren't there relief personnel for us
even at the continent's navel?
(Hathaway)
Quack Salver is
doing what they can, but...
It's wishful thinking.
But if the Base Jabbers are reinforced,
they might be bringing
some new faces we don't know.
(Rod) That would be nice.
You'd pray to God for that?
What about Gawman and the others at Sealuck?
(Golf) They're passing through.
(Hathaway) We can't link up with them until the Wall,
but there seems to be mobile suit reinforcements.
(Golf) Huh...
(Raymond) Mafty can't be taken lightly either, you know.
(Raymond) Tch...
(Emeralda) Too close...
(Raymond)
What? Don't get so embarrassed.
(Iram)
Anyway, once we reach the Wall,
(Emeralda)
Don't be stupid.
(Iram)
Anyway, once we reach the Wall,
there'll be support for the Adelaide attack.
After that, until the Wall,
without getting caught in Kirke's net,
we just have to keep moving.
(Hendrix) The problem is,
from Bynoe Harbour to Navel Point
we'll be operating in three-man cells.
We can't afford to be wiped out.
(Hala) Ah...
(Golf) Whoo...
(Hathaway) Fortunately, the enemy is
hinting at Kwangchow,
so they're not making any obvious move south.
Even so...
(Ridorick)
Well, if the timing's right,
we can hit Kirke's vanguard.
(Hendrix) Since when did Rid become
an optimist?
(Rod) What's in it for us?
(Iram) Nothing.
The self-satisfaction
of having done what we could.
Just self-satisfaction.
I'm sorry, but as we are now,
we have no choice but to move forward.
Bear with me.
(Lane's Mechanic A) Hey, hey.
What's wrong with the colonel's
nerves?!
She's different from the woman
the colonel's been with lately, right?
(Lane's Mechanic C)
She's different! Totally different!
(Lane) Ah!
(Lane's Mechanic C)
Right in front of subordinates about to deploy,
What's the colonel doing?
(Lane, voiceover)
Gigi... So that was her name...
(Lane's Mechanic D)
That's the colonel's good-luck charm, right? That one!
(Lane's Mechanic B)
She came back?
(Lane's Mechanic D) Looks like it.
(Lane, voiceover) A good-luck charm...?
Huh!? ... What the...?
(Lagoid) Move out!
(Lane's Mechanic B)
We'll reach the west route
by nightfall.
(Lane's Mechanic A)
As the colonel said,
I hope we find
Mafty's support base.
Yeah.
(Lane, voiceover) As if you'll find it.
(Gigi) It's an awful place.
So I came back.
I don't care about the Count
anymore.
I understand.
I can't keep you company for a while.
(Gigi) I'm going to Adelaide.
That's right.
Then maybe I'll hide out
at Hathaway's place.
The Count won't come after me
as far as Menado, right?
(Kenneth) I suppose so.
(Kenneth) Where did you put your luggage?
(Gigi) I found a luggage storage place
in Hong Kong.
(Kenneth) I'll have it sent.
You have the claim tag, right?
(Gigi) I'm not sure.
If Hathaway gets mad at me,
I'll have to go back
to Hong Kong, right?
Then
come to me.
I'll work something out.
(Gigi) No.
Something scary happened
in Davao yesterday, right?
(Kenneth)
That was all. Nothing since.
The Adelaide Conference
won't last forever.
Hello!
(Duty Soldier) Uh... ah...
(Gigi) Hmm?
(Kenneth) It's about her.
Can I ask a favor?
(Francine) Huh? ... Yes.
(Kenneth) Hmm?
(Gigi) Shall I step outside?
(footsteps)
(Mace) Shall we depart?
Ah... Gigi Andalusia.
(Kenneth) Yeah.
I'll take Gigi partway too.
(Mace)
Colonel? Lieutenant Colonel Meinzer is—
(Kenneth) Hmm...?
Wait here a moment.
(Kenneth's subordinate) This way.
(Mace) Were you in Davao
this whole time?
(Gigi) No.
I just got back from Hong Kong today.
(Mace)
Then I got back before you.
From Hong Kong—
looking after the VIPs.
Then I got sent to Davao again.
I lost my leave.
(Gigi) When it comes to Mafty countermeasures,
The brass don't want to use people they don't know.
You seem to be well liked by everyone here.
(Gigi) That's what I hated.
(Gigi) The Colonel saved me from that...
is more accurate.
(Mace) Ah...
Men really are children, aren't they?
(Gigi) I wanted to see the Colonel
try his luck as a soldier.
So I stayed by his side.
Luck?
Huh.
So that's why it's a middle-aged guy?
Heh.
The Colonel, you know...
(whispering)
(Gigi) Hehehe, heh, hehehe.
What?!
(slap)
(Meinzer)
The security shift has been changed.
(Kenneth) Hmm?
What is it?
(Francine) Oh, um... um...
(Gigi)
Mace says she's leaving.
To Hong Kong?
(Gigi) Yes...
(Kenneth) You chased her off, huh?
(Gigi) Yeah...
I thought so...
(Gigi) Sorry!
But that woman...
Not now.
She'll drain your energy, Colonel.
I see...
If Gigi says so, it must be true.
In return, I'll stay by the Colonel's side a little longer.
(Kenneth) It's Australia!
(Gigi) Sure.
(English announcement)
(Kenneth)
Well? Think it'll go well?
(Gigi) The whole operation, you mean?
Or this transport plane...?
(Kenneth)
Both. Everything.
(Gigi)
I'm not a fortune teller.
(Officer) Who's that?
(Gigi) But...
I think it'll go well.
Whether you can catch anything of Mafty...
I think it'll slip underwater.
(Kenneth) Underwater?
(Gigi) Something like that...
Something that'll work in your favor, Colonel.
(Kenneth)
Glad to hear you say that.
A person's fortune is something you draw in.
(Liaison A) There were ground troops aboard the carrier,
It seems Man Hunter came in on today's flight, too.
What about the Man Hunter disturbance in Davao?
(Hathaway) I've heard.
(Liaison B) There were quite a few of them,
and Hong Kong types as well.
The order to reinforce Kowloon's security
was a lie.
(Hathaway) Hm...
(Liaison A) What concerns me is
the large amount of electronics—
Large equipment is being transported.
Isn't that for electrical reinforcement
of the conference hall?
No, Adelaide wasn't hit by a colony drop.
There shouldn't be any need
for large-scale reinforcement.
for large-scale reinforcement
(propeller noise)
(Member A) Hey, look!
(Member A) It's here!
(Member B) What is it?
(Fabio)
They say a snake knows a snake's path,
To think we could meet up in a place like this.
So? What is it?
(Fabio) Hmph...
There are plenty of Base Jabbers sitting right there, boss!
Can we borrow a couple?
Then taking Darwin Airport would be easy.
(Hathaway)
A ride to Kowloon?
Heh.
Not Kowloon?
(Hathaway)
Adelaide. It's solid intel.
Hah...
So the ones we had lying low in Darwin...
were all for nothing...
(Hathaway)
What do you say we keep going?
(Fabio)
Why? I thought we weren't going to Ko Chang.
(Hathaway)
Iram.
(Iram)
In other words, if you'll attack
Darwin for us,
we can make it look like Mafty forces
are moving to Ko Chang.
We can create that impression.
(Fabio)
So you're making it look like
you fell for the diversion, then?
(Hathaway)
That's right.
(Chang)
If we use the men standing by at the port,
we can attack Darwin right away.
If you'll give us ten portable
missile launchers,
we'll make it a success.
(Iram)
I'll have them prepared.
(Fabio)
But what about compensation after that?
(Hathaway)
The problem of food supply—
you'll have to negotiate
with Quack Salver.
Will you help them with that?
All right.
Fabio, there are all sorts
of Mafty restrictions, but...
I hope you can accept that.
(Fabio)
Yeah, I know that in my bones.
(distant thunder)
(Hathaway)
Julia.
Hasa.
(Hathaway)
You're staying on the Valiant?
(Julia)
The Xi's maintenance is done,
and what happens after Adelaide
matters too.
(Hathaway)
Besides, even if you don't make the rounds...
I get along with that girl pretty well.
But you know, Hasa, you push
Mafty too hard,
and I feel sorry for Kelia.
(Hathaway)
It can't be helped...
(Julia)
I think she's still around.
(Hathaway)
Huh?
(Julia)
She came with the liaison, didn't she?
I was told not to say, but...
That girl
said she's leaving Mafty
once this is over.
(Hathaway)
Ah!
(running footsteps)
She said, 'Survive...'
(Hathaway breathing heavily)
♪～
(Hathaway, voiceover)
Why
run?
♪ Look
♪ again
♪ falling down
♪ rain
♪ Fading away
♪ Sound
♪ No matter how much I scream
♪ Because it won't reach you
♪ We'd already gone
♪ Even if I unravel it, weakness
♪ A searching voice
♪ Runs like a revolving lantern, over and over
♪ Gazing
♪ Drowning
♪ Even if my heart withers
♪ The two of us turn into the past
♪ Someone's gotta go
♪ No light
♪ At the end of
♪ This hollow
♪ Wind
♪ Growing clear
♪ Left brain
♪ No matter how much I scream
♪ But it won't reach you
♪ We'd already gone
♪ Even if I unravel it, weakness
♪ A searching voice
♪ Runs like a revolving lantern, over and over
♪ Gazing
♪ Drowning
♪ Even if my heart withers
♪ The two of us turn into the past
♪ Someone's gotta go
(Kenneth) Gigi. Gigi.
(noise inside the aircraft)
(noise subsides)
(Kenneth)
We'll be in Darwin soon.
(Gigi) Hm...?
It turned out exactly as Gigi said.
We sank one of Mafty's ships.
Really, Colonel!?
(Kenneth) Yes. It's the ship we call M-3.
I see!
That will thin out Mafty's supply lines considerably.
Yes. She—Gigi Andalusia—
predicted this victory for us.
(Minecche) I see...
(Wave)
I've heard the rumors...
(Kenneth) Well... whether you believe it or not is up to you.
As your commander, I'll take any good omen I can get.
(Gigi) I don't want to get off...
I hate this airport...!
(Kenneth) Ah!
Nn... ugh...
Abort landing!
(Officer A) Huh? Right now?
(Kenneth) Launch aircraft 1 and 2 as well.
(Officer A) But...
(Kenneth) Hurry!!
(Copilot) What's wrong? Respond.
We've lost contact.
(Officer B)
Could it be a Mafty surprise attack...?
(Officer A) The Maftys heading for Kowloon...
Could they have raided Darwin!?
(Kenneth) They don't have the transport capacity
to carry ground troops.
That's probably what they wanted...
What does it feel like?
(Gigi) Hm?
(Minecche) Like you see images?
(Gigi) No, how should I put it...
It's not something that clear...
More like a vague bad feeling...
(Officer B) Colonel, things like this really do happen.
(Kenneth) What?
(Officer B) It's an omen, sir. An omen.
There really are people who bring
that kind of thing with them.
That's what I'm saying.
(Kenneth) You mean me?
(Officer B)
Yes, yes! Exactly.
You're the one who called her here,
aren't you, Colonel?
Gigi Andalucia.
(ringing)
(McGovern) So, did the Director see the footage?
(Yeoksan) Of course.
That would completely undermine
the Federation government's prestige.
The Kimberley unit's mobile suits
grabbing a person and crushing them—
The public must never see that.
(Yeoksan)
I am fully aware of that.
We'll take steps against the station
that aired that video.
(McGovern)
SPTV is a tough network.
That chairman must have a weakness.
(McGovern) In any case, stop that news immediately.
I want nothing more to do with this.
(Yeoksan) Of course.
I will forget it as well.
(McGovern) That's best.
(Yeoksan) Well?
(Female Secretary) The Information and Communications Ministry
will take action, but...
It will take time...
(Yeoksan)
What about my appointment with the Deputy Chief
of the General Staff?
(Hugest)
He says he can see you right now.
(Yeoksan) What floor is he on?
(Hugest) The top floor.
(Yeoksan)
This isn't rural Davao.
If you want to keep seeing this view,
be more careful.
(Hugest) Yes...?
(Hugest) The hijacking was planned by Fabio Rivera.
The ones who had gathered at Oenpelli.
They seem to be a group inspired by Mafty.
(Gigi) Just do it!
They're fakes!
Just as that girl suspected...
(Hugest) What should we do about tracking and apprehending the people involved?
(Yeoksan) Bright Noa's son, huh...
Stand down. Reassign the personnel to Adelaide security.
(Hugest) Understood.
(Revye) Man, I just got here
and this is before I've even had a shower.
When does the minister arrive?
(Revye) Yes, tonight if nothing unusual.
(Yeoksan) You know Kenneth's Kirke unit, don't you?
(Revye) Yes. Tomorrow morning, I hear
he'll be arriving here in person.
(Yeoksan) They've been having a rough time too.
The cabinet ministers only think about their own safety
and keep making unreasonable demands on them.
(Revye) So it seems.
(Yeoksan) ...So, what do you think?
(Revye) About what?
(Yeoksan) About providing cover for the Kirke unit.
The reason they bungled things at Oenpelli
isn't just a problem with the commander.
It's an organizational problem.
Understand?
We need someone with real combat experience immediately.
Bright Noa of the Independent 13th Unit
is a young commander with extensive combat experience, I'd say...
(Revye) I'll look into it.
(combat sounds)
(explosion)
(Iram) What's burning?
(Hathaway) A pile of garbage.
(Iram) How did it catch fire...?
(Hathaway) It's Hala's mobile suit.
Hm...
(Iram) Rod and Hendrix should be with Hala.
(Iram) We'd better assume it's the enemy's movement route.
Let's go.
(Iram) It's around here.
(electronic beep)
(Iram) There it is!
(bird chirping)
(Hathaway) Whoa!
(Hathaway) Then Rod, too...
(Hendrix) I'm sorry...
I couldn't save them...
(Hathaway) You shook off the enemy pursuit
and made it here. That alone is remarkable, Hendrix.
(Hendrix)
Thank you...
(Hathaway) The Valiant...
(Iram) Why do the good ones
always die first?
(Raymond) Doesn't mean he's dead.
(Maximilian) Even the Federation
wouldn't kill a man for fleeing a sinking ship.
(Emeralda) That's right...
Besides,
it's not all bad...
I hear Fabio Rivera
pulled it off well.
(Hathaway) I see. He pulled it off.
(Iram) You've got good friends.
(Hathaway) Yeah...
(Hathaway) I wonder if Gawman
and the others are doing all right.
(Iram) You get some sleep first.
I'll go check on a few things.
(Hathaway) Please.
(door closes)
(Hathaway) It was just awful...
Right?
Quess.
Compared to this...
Kelia was nothing more than
a trivial worldly act.
And as for Gigi...
It's a disgrace...
Hah! Ah!
Ahhh... Ahhh!
Ah! Ah! Ugh...
(Minecche)
Your luggage arrived ahead of you.
How fortunate.
(Gigi) Where will the colonel
be sleeping?
(Minecche) He has work again tonight,
so he'll be up late.
He's on that floor
where the lights are on.
This entire area has been
requisitioned by the military.
Except for running errands
for your boyfriend.
The hotel shouldn't complain either. Heh heh.
Heh heh.
(Gigi) Thank you.
(Minecche)
...And what do you think?
Do you sense what lies ahead?
(Gigi)
Let's see... Well, all will be fine...
Oh-ho-ho!
But I'm not a prophet, you know.
Yes, I understand.
Please rest well tonight.
Please show me
that new power again sometime.
(Gigi, voiceover) Things are
a little off.
I think today's events
were just the colonel's luck.
He's a capable commander.
He does prepare
where you can't see it.
Hathaway and the others
are the ones improvising.
He's always struggling,
standing on tiptoe.
(Cardeas)
There's something I left undone...
There is something I must do.
(Secretary) Please wait.
(Sons) Father!
(Son) Move.
(Gigi, voiceover) How sad…
Until death,
plagued by succession and inheritance.
A man everyone
hopes will die soon…
It's decided…
I have a father complex…
(Kenneth) Gigi!
(Gigi) Huh…
(Kenneth) It's a nice room.
Who'd have thought a hotel like this
would remain here.
We got lucky.
Ah…
(Gigi) It is.
Let's head out…
Among the top officials
of the Federation government,
there are those who own tens of thousands
of acres of land around here
under their own names, apparently.
(Gigi) What's that?
Status!
It's what people ultimately desire.
That means those kinds of people
are inside the government.
Oh, gross.
Why do adults end up like that?
(Kenneth) Though humans are animals,
the heart desires to exist
outside the cycle of life and death.
I see…
(Kenneth) But
that it is eternal—
there's no guarantee of that
in the real world.
What can a person take with them when they die?
(Gigi, voiceover)
Do what you can only do while young.
That's why I'm going.
(Gigi) Colonel.
Do you know anything
about Colonel Heyman?
(Kenneth) What's wrong?
All of a sudden…
I just hope the Kirke unit's
last unresolved issue
gets resolved…
(Kenneth) You say the strangest things.
(Gigi) Near here,
there's a place called Ayers Rock,
isn't there?
Tomorrow morning,
I wonder if I can see it
before we leave.
I want to do some sightseeing.
Does this have something to do
with Kimberley?
(Gigi) I don't know.
It just came to me.
(Kimberley) This is Air Force Commander
Kimberley Heyman.
We will, from the South Pacific airspace,
achieve the complete elimination
of anti-Federation forces.
Keep in step with the Criminal Police Organization...
(Mira) To Earth? When?
(Bright)
I'm leaving early in the morning
the day after tomorrow.
(Mira) That day, we're going
to New Hampshire Sea.
to see a shop...
(Bright) That's true, but...
Couldn't you go tomorrow instead?
(Mira) Did you really
submit your resignation to the military?
(Bright) Yeah.
I got a promise
that this will be the last time.
that this will be the last time
(phone ringing)
(Mira) Yes... that's right.
About the lakefront tenant viewing
the day after tomorrow...
Would first thing
tomorrow afternoon work?
Can you spare the time?
(Bright) I'll make time!
I'll make the higher-ups agree to it.
(Mira) That's fine.
Please go ahead.
(Mira)
Was the Oenpelli matter the direct cause?
(Bright) I suppose so...
Even though you have
military force like an elephant
if they swarm around you
like ants
how you should control
your own power
is a difficult problem.
(Mira) Well, that's true...
(sound of a kiss)
(Mira) You may get to see Hathaway.
(Bright)
Yeah... once the operation's over,
the island where he's doing
plant fieldwork—
I'll try to stop by.
(Mira) What about dinner tonight?
(Bright)
No, but I'll definitely come home.
(Mira)
I see... take care.
(Kenneth) Listen up!
A Mafty deployment is possible.
At a place as conspicuous
as Ayers Rock,
we never imagined Mafty
would be hiding there,
but she showed us
that possibility!
Don't let your guard down!
(Pilots) Sir!
(Kenneth)
They're veterans you can trust.
What's that?
(Gigi) While watching the sunrise,
we all have breakfast together.
(Kenneth) I'll arrange lunch
in Adelaide.
(Gigi) I'm counting on you, Colonel.
(Wave) Ms. Gigi! Here you go.
(Minecche)
Colonel, you need to hurry.
(Kenneth) I know.
(Lane's Mechanic B)
He came up through the technical track—
That's how a senile colonel does things.
(Lane, voiceover)
That alone shows how much this unit's existence...
The world of the adults
running this unit
is warped.
There's no way Mafty
would be at a tourist spot!
I don't believe it.
Damn it!
(Mechanic) Ms. Gigi.
It's in sight.
(Gigi) That's Ayers Rock...
(Lowaist) All hands, evacuate!
We're heading for the wall, as planned!
(Hathaway) Lo!
(Hathaway) See you!
(Raymond) We're counting on you!
(Hathaway) Ready?
(Lowaist)
The connect area is tight.
I've sent the position to Maxi.
(Hathaway) Sorry...
(Lowaist) The rear guard
never says 'sorry.'
(Maximilian)
The positions are already registered.
You can do it!
(Hathaway) I hope so.
(Fabio)
Hey, Mafty!
You all right?
(Hathaway)
I'll hold them off! Go!
(Fabio)
Yeah! Don't you die on me!
(Lowaist) Two enemy units!
One Base Jabber!
All Galcezon units,
maintain low altitude
Use Ayers Rock as cover
and proceed southwest.
(Hathaway) So this is it...
(Lowaist)
The remote control's sensitivity is tight.
Comm range is limited. In other words...
(Hathaway) I get close, lock on,
and fire.
(Lowaist) Exactly!
(Hathaway) I'll give it a try!
(Lowaist) All right! Withdraw!
(Hathaway) I'll overcome them—
the mundane world,
and carnal desire!!
(Gigi) Ahh!
(Hathaway)
It really is that simple...
(alarm)
(Hathaway) What?!
(Hathaway) Impressive!
(alarm)
(Gigi) Uhhh...
(Hathaway) Another one!
(Hathaway) Nn... nnh...
Nn! A new model?!
(alarm)
(rapid gunfire)
(Hathaway) Uoooaah!
(Lane)
It's not that I trusted him.
Not Gigi...
I sensed it!
(Hathaway) Lane Aim!?
(Lane) Ah...
Ngh! Dammit!!
(Lane) You fake Gundam!
(Lane) Only skill matters...
Luck, predictions...
As if such things
could settle it!
(Lane) Hah!!
Ngh!! Guh...!
Ngh!! Whoa!
(Hathaway) He dodged!
Lane Aim... Nngh...
(Lane) Guh!
(Hathaway) But...!
(rapid gunfire)
(alarm)
After all,
it's a trainer...
If I don't pull back, I'll be shot down...
(alarm)
Ugh!! Ngh!
(Hathaway) Huh!?
(heavy breathing)
(Haro) Haro
(Amuro)
It's the third one, but take good care of it.
(Hathaway) Of course!
(Amuro) Let's go!
(Lane) You again!
Hostages, fortune-telling, traps...
The adults are—!
(Lane) What are you playing at?!
(Hathaway) I'm not like you!
Huh? What?
(Hathaway) Unlike you,
I'm not just a pilot!
Amuro Ray!
(Amuro) If you're so great,
then use political power
to crush the Federation Government!
You, who can't take one step
outside the military!
What are you playing at?
(Amuro) Hathaway Noa!
The son of a man who fought
Earth's enemies alongside us—
Why are you here?!
Because I've figured out the true nature
of the people who remain on Earth!
The people who promoted space emigration
They're monopolizing Earth
all for themselves!
(Hathaway) Enough to swallow
all of humanity's ego...
The Earth isn't that big!
(Amuro) Human wisdom can overcome
something like that.
Ahh!
(Hathaway) Then!
Right now—to all you ignorant masses—
show me you can bestow wisdom!
(Amuro) That's
his line!
Hathaway Noa!
You'd side with the man
who took Quess?!
(Hathaway) Ah... Quess...
(Hathaway) Ugh...
Ugh... stop... ahh... ngh...
Ugh... ngh...
(Amuro) Hathaway,
the darkness that dwells within him—
he's ashamed of that dark part.
(Both) It's self-loathing.
(Hathaway) I...
(Both) When shown kindness,
he felt only humiliation.
(Hathaway) I—!
(Both)
But Quack Salver
shone light on the darkness.
(Hathaway) Mafty...
(Both)
It gave his life meaning and purpose.
(Hathaway) Justice is merciless.
(Both) Blaming himself,
he keeps atoning like this,
fighting evil and injustice.
(Hathaway) Sometimes sacrifice is necessary.
(Both)
That's no excuse.
(Amuro) Hathaway!
(Hathaway)
Yes, I know.
That was my fault.
(rapid gunfire)
(Hathaway)
Ah... ah... ugh...
Ngh...
(Quess) Hathaway?
(Hathaway)
I must not be forgiven.
Hathaway!
(Hathaway) Punish me...
(Amuro)
Hathaway Noa!
Don't say his name, Amuro!
(Quess) Ahh!
(alarm)
(Lane) Whoa! Aaargh!
(Lane) Ngh!
(alarm)
(Lane) Ngh! ...Weapons...
(Lane) Ngh...
(Hathaway's breathing)
(Lane)
Uuh! Ugh... Aaargh!
(Gigi) That's enough.
(Hathaway) Hah!
(incoming transmission beep)
(Pilot) I surrender!
(Pilot) I won't resist!
Spare my life!
(Wave) Ms. Gigi!
I am Gigi Andalucia.
I am connected to Boundenwood.
I'll make a good hostage, won't I?
(Hathaway)
That you are that person—
We have neither the information nor the means to believe it.
Then...
(Gigi) Then you should become a god.
(Hathaway)
Gigi Andalucia...
(Hathaway) Is that all?
(Hathaway) Why... are you here now...?
(Gigi) Mm!
Hathaway!
(Hathaway) Ugh!
(Gigi) Ahh!
You're the only one wearing one of those!
(Gigi) Ah...
(Hathaway) C-Come on!
(Gigi) Ahh!
Throw yourself toward me.
Toward Hathaway...?
(Hathaway)
That's right. Don't think about anything else.
Go for it! One, two, three!
(Gigi) Ahh! Mm...
Ahh... ahh... Hah... hah...
(Hathaway)
What are you doing here—of all places?
(Gigi) Because—!
(Hathaway) Huh!?
♪～
♪ She's got a smile
that it seems, to me
♪ Reminds me of childhood memories
♪ Where everything was
as fresh as the bright blue sky (Sky)
♪ Now and then, when I see her face
♪ She takes me away
to that special place
♪ And if I stared too long,
I'd probably break down and cry
♪ Woah-woah-woah
Sweet child of mine
♪ Woah, oh-oh-oh
Sweet love of mine
♪ She's got eyes of the bluest skies
♪ As if they thought of rain
♪ I'd hate to look into those eyes
♪ and see an ounce of pain
♪ Her hair reminds me
of a warm, safe place
♪ Where as a child, I'd hide
♪ And pray for the thunder
♪ and the rain to quietly pass me by
♪ Woah-oh-woah
Sweet child of mine
♪ Ooh-woah, oh-oh-oh
Sweet love of mine
♪ Woah-oh-woah
Sweet child of mine
♪ Ooh-woah, oh-oh-oh
Sweet love of mine
♪ Woah, oh-oh-oh
Sweet child of mine
♪ ooh, yeah-eh
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
Sweet love of mine
(Officer A) This airport will become
the command base for the defense of Adelaide.
(Officer B) The Big Carrier...
Mafty?
(Kenneth) Hm!
I would have liked to see
a little more of people's fortunes...
Gigi...
♪ Where do we go?
♪ Where do we go now?
♪ Mm-mm, oh, where do we go?
♪ Oh, where do we go now?
(Where do we go?)
♪ Where do we go? (Sweet child)
♪ Mm-huh, where do we go now?
♪ Ah-yah-yah-yah-yah-yah-yah-yah-oh
(Where do we go? Where do we go?)
♪ Ooh, where do we go now?
(Where do we go?)
♪ Uh-uh-uh, uh-uh-uh-oh, wow
♪ Where do we go?
♪ Oh-oh, where do we go now?
♪ (Oh) Where do we go,
oh-oh-oh-oh? (Oh, wow)
♪ Where do we go now?
♪ Where do we go?
♪ Woah-oh, where do we go now?
♪ No, no, no, no, no, no, no
♪ Sweet child
♪ Sweet child of mine